So create a new project from over here.
You project.
I'm gonna search my boat, SDM 32.
Four one one.
If you have the Air Force, you were one.
That is fine if it's in a disco type board.
Yeah.
You would find the USPTO, the extra USP we need on this side.
Okay.
So we can open our project.
I'm gonna start off by clearing or out.
Click over here, clip out, I'll say yes.
Right.
So are we going to configure our port to serve as a mon's on HIIT mode?
So we start off by setting the USP to a device we use in the device mode.
So USP should be on the connectivity over here.
USP underscore all TGF is a collective.
And then this select device only like this.
OK.
And we can see as soon as we do that the political opinions.
P, A twelve and P eleven.
These are the US B parents.
They've been selected.
Next, we've got to configure the clock.
And with USP development, the clock is very important.
We want to use the, um, the bypass clock source from the RCC.
And this will give us the clock source from our debugger.
Remember that the school board has two chips.
It's got a debugger side in the main side.
Okay.
So I'll come over here.
RACC and then expand this.
And then H.
SC here.
High speed extend or oscillate.
Bypass Luxor's like this.
OK.
And then it selected those as well.
So once we have selected our USP as device only, we've got to select the class.
We do that in the middle way over here.
So Klecko Middle Way here and then USP device.
And then over here.
Oh, select H.I.G., which is human interface device class.
Like this.
So to make this a bit more interest in what is going to happen is that I'm going to enable the push
button on the disco board so that when I press it, that mounts.
My most points are on.
The computer would move like this.
And the push button is connected to this, connected to the P zero.
So come over here.
P is you.
And then oh said this as GPL you input like this.
We can see over here the eye wall clock configuration has issues.
That's why there's this red market.
We can come here and fix it.
It says, Do you want to run?
Automatic lock issue.
Fix it.
I'll say yes.
And it's attempting to fix it.
OK?
It's selected it so this two eight is selected the HSC for us.
High speed external.
And then, um, this we can bump it up a bit.
We can push you to one hundred hertz or 100 megahertz.
See?
It says, no solution found use in deselected sources.
Do you want to use a source?
I'll click.
Okay.
Here.
What is important is that our HSC is selected and the input is eight, um, eight hertz, the input
frequency.
Okay.
So it's just gonna be change in the other part to see, um, if it doesn't.
I may have to just keep it at seven to two or perhaps just, um, set it up to ninety six.
OK, so I've said it to 96.
And this we were able to find a solution that works.
I'll come back to Piñon configuration.
And this is, um, our you at.
And, uh, this is or our USP.
There's the perimeter set.
And so we keep everything the same.
By default, when we generate this code, the H.I.G. device is going to be a Mones remix to generate
amount's for us.
So we wouldn't change anything in this project.
That descriptor here gives the information.
It gives the M the vendor ID number and PDU product ID number.
So on your computer, if you go to your device manager and you see there's a USB device connected with
his product ID number, then we know it is our port that we've connected.
Okay.
Also, I should mention, um, this product ID number.
Um, this is a reserved number for this particular product.
So if you create your own product, a different HIIT device, like a media player or something else,
you would you would generate your own product ID number, and then you would have to inform the manufacturers
of the operating systems such as Windows and OSX to know this number, such that whenever your device
is connected to the operating system, the drivers can be loaded automatically.
Right.
So this is what most products ID on.
This is the most product ID number.
If you start a company, you build your own USP devices to, you would have to pay for a vendor ID number,
which we find over here.
Right.
This one is provided to us by S-T.
And you may want to change this drink to the name of your company, manufacturing screen manufacturer
String.
So the company name over here is S.T. We can keep it the same product screen and then other things.
Right.
So go ahead and generate the code.
Click over here, generate code and then I'll give this project a name.
USP underscore each I.D. and this call mouse.
And then also like this SDM 32 Kubi E.
Click over here to generate the code.
So what our project, I'm going to clean it up a bit.
By reducing the amount of comment in here.
Clean this away.
This as well.
And then this.
I'll take this out as well.
This.
Take this also out.
OK.
So this is it.
This is what we have.
We know our USP files were stored in a different folder.
We can go to the SDM device library.
Now we have another like, uh, we have another forwarder here known as the, um.
The middle where.
The middle warehouse.
Our USP device.
Library.
Yeah.
For us when we check.
We have the class which deals with the class.
We're dealing with HIV class.
And then they call us the USP device called a USP device.
Uh, requires an eye or request control request.
And I will request.
And then we have other files here for the device, the configuration and then the descriptor.
So to send in a mouse related information from our mouths, which is our microcontroller to our to a
computer, which is, you know, the computer that I'm running.
We first need to create a buffer to store that information so we can store information with regards
to the X position, the Y position that click left, click right, click, et cetera.
So I'm gonna create a buffer here known as Mount's Buffer.
So I'll see you in eight.
Underscore T over here and then I'll call this mouse on a scope of uh and the size here will be for
like this.
So we said we're going to check if the, um, the button is pressed.
And then we would move the pointer to do that.
We can check over here.
We can use an if statement to check if the, um, the push button is press or I can simply say if and
then the function to use for the GPL you is how GPL you read Pean, GPL, you underscore here
GPL, you on the school.
Read PIN again, this takes the port, which is G.P.A. you, eh?
And then the pain cheapie, you underscore pain, underscore zero because we're dealing with P zero.
If this will read and it's pressed if GPL you pin a course set, then we.
We're gonna send the HIV report.
So to send a report, we have to find the API for doing that.
And to send a report, we have to find the API and we can find it from the.
Which I did not see far.
So the H I did a but C file.
We come over here to our SD Middleware S-T device library H.I.G. and there should be source over here,
which I did not see here.
And this also gives the um, the descriptor, the descriptor file that describes the, um.
The data.
The data size and the meaning of the various data.
This is the report descriptor.
This here encapsulates all the information required to process the size of data and the meaning.
Okay.
So we looking for the, um, the Senate report, each I.D..
Send a report function which would allow us to send a report to the computer.
It should be down here somewhere.
OK, so there's the sand report function.
The brief says U.S. PD, meaning divides us, BP and the score.
Each I.D. and reports send each idea report in the first parameter.
Here is the device instance.
The second parameter is to point out to the report and then it returns the status.
This there is a third parameter, the length of the report.
So the report basically has the information.
We all your X value, your Y value, your click right and left click.
So you take this, you put it in a buffer and then you send it to the computer and then it's going to
move the mouse accordingly.
So in a row, that example, you can understand that there is this report constantly being sent rapidly
to the computer such that a computer mouse can move flawlessly.
Right.
So I'm going to copy this function over here and then go back to our main dot see file.
Pasted over here.
We, uh, we can clean the argument.
It takes three arguments.
In fact, I'll clean these lines so that I can disclose this from here.
So we need to put three arguments here.
The first argument is the the instant.
So we need the first I comment is the, um, the handle, the USP device handle.
And then, um, so something to do with a device.
It should be found in our device or CFL.
Um, we have a device to see if all of a here.
Let's see if it is defined here.
OK?
So let us be cool on the declaration.
So we have to pass this as the first argument to our sand report to function.
I'm gonna copy this controversy to copy and then paste this over here.
It has to be, um, the first argument takes the stress of the handle.
And then the second argument is to buffer our buffer, smallest buffer.
And then the length, which is four.
Okay, so one thing.
Um.
Okay, let's put a bit of delay, so that demotes point out doesn't run away.
Copperhill DeLay and then I'll say delay.
It borders two hundred milliseconds.
Right.
Then, um, yeah, it's looking fine.
So, no, we've got to set the the position we want to move.
You know what?
No, a buffer.
So we said we want to move.
Um, I think we want to move the pointer.
We don't want to click.
So index number one will be used for doing that.
Is used for doing that.
It's not because we want to use index number one, the index for doing that index number one.
So I'll come here and then, um, I'll simply say, um.
I see Mones, the name of the Beaufoy is most buffa.
Index zero here or pursue index one here or pause one hundred.
And then index to here, I'll pass you, I just want to, you know, move it then index three here.
Opas, you as well.
Okay, so this buffer is going to be sent, right?
There's the site so we can build and see what we have.
And I'm going to click here to build a project.
And then, um, we have three arrows, it says this one here, um, undeclared, undeclared.
Yes, indeed, it's undeclared.
We got it from the USP device.
Dot see.
Okay.
This was declared locally in the U.S. device.
Those C.
Uh, let's see.
I'm going to copy this and declared as some extent in my mind, that sea controversy and then.
Bring it here.
I'll see extern.
Okay, no click here to build.
It's in.
And it seems you cannot find the, um, the dysfunction USP device.
He tried to report as well.
So, um, I'm going to include USP, H.I.G. Dot h.
Over here.
Yes.
H.I.G. dot h.
Include.
USP to underscore H.I.G., but H.
Okay, let's build again.
Click over here.
OK.
No, we have no arrow.
No warning.
I'm going to connect it to the second USP, to my to my disco board, to the site.
I showed you earlier and then connect it to my computer and let's see if it works.
So I'm going to click here to debunk I've connected my USP.
I'll click here to debug.
And then I select this over here.
And then I say, okay, over here.
It's Lodin.
Placates, St.Louis, successful.
Going to click here to run and I'm going to press the push button.
OK.
Nothing is happening thus far.
Right.
Um, the reason it's no movement is from the clock set.
I suspect one of you have having these issues, which regards to, um, um, precise or high speed peripherals,
such as, um, the USP.
You should check your clock.
So we'll check that.
But before we go, I'll just explain, um, what these buffer's mean here.
You may wonder, why do we have four?
So this one will be for sending click information.
This will be for click.
And this will be for X motion.
And then, um, this for Y motion.
You can experiment with these later once we sort out our clock issue.
So if you want to send a particular Y motion, you can pass it to indexed to if you want to send a scroll
wheel motion.
Click.
Okay.
So we're going to regenerate our code.
And the, um, the bad thing about cleaning the comment is when you clean the comment and you regenerate
your code, everything is going to be wiped off.
The main function is going to be a new one.
But if we had followed the comment blocks and placed our code where the Cuba mix advises us to place
when we regenerate, what could we be kept?
But because we didn't do that, we are going to do a trick.
I'm going to copy all of our information from the top of the main dot C followed by here.
I'm gonna copy from here to the end of it.
We need to copy all of this to the, uh.
On to the end of the world.
One loop over here.
So I'm copying from top over here.
Main dot h.
To the end of here.
I'm going to copy all of this.
So now keep this in my clipboard and then would regenerate.
What's gonna happen is when we generate the new code was going to change.
Is the content of this function here, because this is the core configuration function, because I don't
want to change it to my own.
I'm doing it with you.
Okay, so let's go back to Cuba.
Max, I'm going to go to Cuba, Max.
Currently, um, our clock is at HSC bypass clock source.
I'm going to click this drop down and select ceramic resonator here and then.
We're going to use the ceramic resonator crystals like ceramic resonator, if you have the SDM 32 to
four new aboard board four Discovery Boat.
Yeah, this should be fine.
For one.
To be specific.
Other boats.
I just hope you don't face any issues.
And I'm going to keep everything here the same.
And I'm going to come to project manager and then just click generate and it's going to regenerate the
code.
And then we can keep this.
We don't need to open it.
We already have our project here.
We already have our project in Cuba mix.
And we see replace.
OK.
So now you can see everything that's being replaced.
Our main dot C file.
Our main function is almost empty.
Order could we wrote disappeared.
But because we've copied it, we can just replace.
I'm just going to delete everything here cause we copied this before we regenerated.
So clean this place, this over here like this.
And then I'm going to build the project.
It's Putin.
And this time, once the building is complete, I'm actually going to test this on a different computer
because I'm using the, um, the fast USB port on my computer for my external hard disk for recording
this video.
I wouldn't have access to the USB port, so I'm going to take a second computer and connect my nuke
my disco board and use it as if it were a mouse.
Once this is done, I'm going to click this bug over here and this would download a code once it downloads
our exit the debugger and then pull out the new clue.
Pull out the disco board from my computer and and plug it into the computer.
And shoot the video with my phone.
OK, says Download, verified successfully.
Right.
So I'm just going to click here to exit.
You can see over here.
This is.
She can see over here.
This is my school board.
And then I've connected the, um, the USP.
This is just for power.
This is the D-Box side is connected to one side of the computer.
This is the, um, the USB device side connected to the other USB port of the computer.
And then, um, we have a real push button, which is blue over here.
This is so push button over here like this.
My finger is pointing at it and I'm going to press the push button.
And I you can see the, um, the pointer move on the screen.
It's run away.
Bring it back to the center.
Press the push button and you can see the pointer jump.
Right.
So this is it.
I'm testing on a different computer.
OK.
So this order is.